Productivity comes from all the things
that you choose not to do.
I see commitment as the elimination of alternatives.
If I get married, then I eliminate all alternatives
to the person that I'm married to, right?
That is commitment, which is very similar to focus.
If you think about the hypothetical extreme of focus
is that somebody does literally nothing but one thing.
So they don't eat, they don't sleep,
they would eventually die.
But they would be 100% focused
during the time that they were alive.
Obviously we have to put a couple things in,
you have to eat food, you have to sleep, right?
But the most focused person
does the fewest things outside
of the thing they're focused on.